Register of the Leo Eloesser Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1892-1984.; See also Oversize Materials
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser and nurses from the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy, Spain, ca. 1938 (Folder 31: 27)
  - One print depicting a banquet in honor of Leo Eloesser, San Leandro, California, 1938 September 17. (Folder 31: 28)
    Photograph includes Eloesser
  - Five prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others, San Francisco, 1940 (Folder 31: 29)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser on a working visit to a hospital in Latin America, 1942 (Folder 31: 30)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with a dachshund, and one print depicting only the dog, San Francisco, 1942 September. (Folder 31: 31)
    Also includes a watercolor by Eloesser depicting dachshunds
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with other participants at a medical congress, Latin America, 1943 (Folder 31: 32)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser with others in Huipulco, Mexico, 1943 September (Folder 31: 33)
  - Eight prints depicting Leo Eloesser with others in Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1943 November (Folder 31: 34)
  - Four prints depicting Leo Eloesser with others in Montevideo, Uruguay, 1944 (Folder 31: 35)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with Tom Earnfred, Michael Jeffrey, Marjorie Trumbull, and Peggy Wood, San Francisco, 1944 February (Folder 31: 36)
  - Twenty-two prints depicting Leo Eloesser in China as part of a medical relief mission, ca. 1945-1948 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Fifteen prints depicting scenes in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 2)
    Two prints depict Leo Eloesser
  - Twenty-five prints depicting scenes in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 3)
    One print depicts Leo Eloesser
  - Nine prints depicting an obstetrics class taught by Leo Eloesser, China, ca. 1945-1948 (Folder 32: 4)
  - Thirty-nine prints depicting scenes relating to medical relief in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 5)
    Seven prints depict Leo Eloesser
  - Twenty-two prints depicting scenes relating to medical relief in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 6)
    Four prints depict Leo Eloesser
  - Twenty-seven prints depicting scenes relating to medical relief in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 7)
  - Twenty-three prints depicting scenes relating to medical relief in China, ca. 1945-1948. (Folder 32: 8)
  - Thiry-two prints depicting scenes largely relating to medical relief in China, including classes taught by Leo Eloesser, ca. 1945-1948 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Forty-four prints depicting scenes largely relating to medical relief in China, including classes taught by Leo Eloesser, ca. 1945-1948 (Folder 32: 10)
  - Twenty-two prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others, Darbyshire, England, 1947 (Folder 32: 11)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser, New York, 1947 April (Folder 32: 12)
  - Thirty-two prints depicting scenes largely relating to medical relief in china, including classes taught by Leo Eloesser, ca. 1948 (Folder 32: 13)
  - Thirty-nine prints depicting scenes largely relating to medical relief in China, including classes taught by Leo Eloesser, 1948. (Folder 32: 14)
    Two prints depict Eloesser. Includes a list of photographs compiled for Joyce Campbell by Newton Rowell Bowles, 1985
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser in Mexico, ca. 1950 (Folder 32: 15)
  - Ten prints relating to a visit to Brazil by Leo Eloesser, 1950 (Folder 32: 16)
    Two prints depict Eloesser
  - Six prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others sailing on San Francisco Bay, 1951. (Folder 32: 17)
    Includes one print depicting Harry Bridges
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser in Montreal, Canada, 1952 (Folder 32: 18)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser with the Stackpole family, 1952 (Folder 32: 19)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser in Guadalajara, Mexico, 1953 January (Folder 32: 20)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with others, Panama, 1953 December (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, 1955 (Folder 33: 2)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, 1956 September (Folder 33: 3)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Dave Wood, 1957 August (Folder 33: 4)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser and Manuel Bastos Ansart(?), 1959 September (Folder 33: 5)
  - Five prints depicting Leo Eloesser with others, Apatzingan, Mexico, 1959 November (Folder 33: 6)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser sailing on San Francisco Bay, 1960 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Five prints depicting Leo Eloesser on a visit to Ireland, 1961 (Folder 33: 8)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with Dr. and Sra. Carlos Noble, Mexico, 1961 April (Folder 33: 9)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, Mexico, 1963 (Folder 33: 10)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser and Russel Lee, 1963 (Folder 33: 11)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser lecturing in Italy, 1963 September (Folder 33: 12)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Joyce Campbell, Rome, Italy, 1963 September (Folder 33: 13)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others, 1964 (Folder 33: 14)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser on a working visit to Montevideo, Uruguay, 1966 (Folder 33: 15)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and others, 1969 April 13 (Folder 33: 16)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Joyce Campbell, ca. 1970 (Folder 33: 17)
  - Six prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others, ca. 1970 (Folder 33: 18)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, 1970 (Folder 33: 19)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser, Tacámbuco, Mexico, 1970 July (Folder 33: 20)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and others, Antibes, France, 1970 August (Folder 33: 21)
  - Twelve prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others at a medical conference, Mexico(?), 1971 April (Folder 33: 22)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser, Leningrad, 1971 August (Folder 33: 23)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, 1972. (Folder 33: 24)
    Portrait by Hebe Stackpole
  - Seven prints depicting Leo Eloesser and Joyce Campbell with others during a trip to the People's Republic of China, 1973 October (Folder 33: 25)
  - Four prints depicting Leo Eloesser and Joyce Campbell, Tucson, Arizona, 1974 February 20 (Folder 33: 26)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, ca. 1975 (Folder 33: 27)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser, 1975. (Folder 33: 28)
    Portraits taken by Imogen Cunningham
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Russel Lee, 1975 (Folder 33: 29)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Newton Rowell Bowles, 1975 September (Folder 33: 30)
  - Four prints depicting Arthur and Molly Eloesser (parents), 1925-1932 (Folder 33: 31)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser (grandfather), undated (Folder 33: 32)
  - Five prints depicting Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 33: 33)
  - One print depicting Joyce Campbell with Marika Belitini, Jack Charnow, Yvette Dupois, and Ellen Frisova, Paris, France, 1949 July (Folder 33: 34)
  - Two prints depicting Joyce Campbell and Bill Sutch, ca. 1950 (Folder 33: 35)
  - Six prints depicting Joyce Campbell, New York, 1951 (Folder 33: 36)
  - One print depicting Joyce Campbell, 1952 (Folder 33: 37)
  - Seven prints depicting Joyce Campbell, Mexico(?), 1954 May (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - One print depicting Joyce Campbell, Mexico, 1958 (Folder 34: 2)
  - One print depicting Joyce Campbell, 1975. (Folder 34: 3)
    Portrait by Imogen Cunningham
  - Eight prints depicting Joyce Campbell and others on a trip to China, 1984 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Five prints depicting classmates of Leo Eloesser, Heidelberg, Germany, 1906 (Folder 34: 5)
  - One print depicting James Campbell and others, 1911 February 12 (Folder 34: 6)
  - One print depicting Jack and Mary(?) Gibbon, 1942 (Folder 34: 7)
  - One print depicting Chu Teh, ca. 1945 (Folder 34: 8)
  - Two prints depicting Juan Soto Blanco, 1945 (Folder 34: 9)
  - One print depicting Choh-luh and Isabel Li, 1945 August (Folder 34: 10)
  - Six prints depicting Bill Sutch, ca. 1950 (Folder 34: 11)
  - One print depicting Giulio Minetti, 1951 December (Folder 34: 12)
  - One print depicting Enrique Cosio-Pascal, 1952 (Folder 34: 13)
  - One print depicting John Albert Toepfer, 1952 (Folder 34: 14)
  - One print depicting Mrs. A. M. Campbell, ca. 1953 (Folder 34: 15)
  - Two prints depicting E. Haro, 1954 (Folder 34: 16)
  - One print depicting Dr. and Sra. Pardó, 1958 (Folder 34: 17)
  - One print depicting William and Maia Dock, 1960 (Folder 34: 18)
  - Two prints depicting Ernest Bacon, 1961 (Folder 34: 19)
  - One print depicting Dr. Carlos Noble, 1965 (Folder 34: 20)
  - Four prints depicting a memorial celebration for Richard Barthelemy, 1988 (Folder 34: 21)
  - Two prints depicting Dr. and Mrs. Barkan, undated (Folder 34: 22)
  - One print depicting Columbus Bries, undated (Folder 34: 23)
  - One print depicting Art Campbell, undated (Folder 34: 24)
  - One print depicting Mr. and Mrs. Charles Campbell, undated (Folder 34: 25)
  - One print depicting Samuel Fine, undated (Folder 34: 26)
  - One print depicting Otto Heynemann, undated (Folder 34: 27)
  - One print depicting David Tien and family, undated (Folder 34: 28)
  - Three prints depicting Art Young, undated (Folder 34: 29)
  - Five prints depicting unidentified persons, possibly relatives of Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 34: 30)
  - Six prints depicting unidentified persons, possibly relatives of Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 34: 31)
  - One print depicting a young girl, possibly a relative of Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 34: 32)
  - Two prints depicting unidentified persons, possibly relatives of Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 34: 33)
  - Two prints depicting an unidentified young woman, 1917 (Folder 34: 34)
  - One print depicting an unidentified man, 1932 (Folder 34: 35)
  - One print depicting two unidentified persons, 1936 (Folder 34: 36)
  - Two prints depicting musicians, Mexico(?), ca. 1950 (Folder 34: 37)
  - Eight prints depicting scenes of ranch life, Tacámbaro, Mexico, 1966 (Folder 34: 38)
  - One print depicting Diego Rivera at work on a mural, undated (Folder 35: 1)
  - One print depicting a Diego Rivera sketch of Mr. and Mrs. Ralph Stackpole, 1927 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Six prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, 1952. (Folder 35: 3)
    Two prints are signed by Rivera
  - Twelve prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated. (Folder 35: 4)
    Photographs by Tina Modotti
  - Seven prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated. (Folder 35: 5)
  - One print depicting a mural by Diego Rivera, undated. (Folder 35: 6)
    Photograph by Manuel Alvarez Bravo
  - Eleven prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, New Workers' School, New York, undated (Folder 35: 7)
  - Eight prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, New Workers' School, New York, undated (Folder 35: 8)
  - Nine prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, Detroit, Michigan, undated (Folder 35: 9)
  - Eight prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, Detroit, Michigan, undated (Folder 35: 10)
  - Five prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, Detroit, Michigan, undated (Folder 35: 11)
  - Ten prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 12)
  - Seven prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 13)
  - Seven prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 14)
  - Seven prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 15)
  - Eight prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 16)
  - Eight prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 17)
  - Six prints depicting murals by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 35: 18)
  - One print depicting a self-portrait by Frida Kahlo, undated (Folder 35: 19)
  - One print depicting a stage coach in Calistoga, California, ca. 1890 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Eight prints depicting scenes in Hungary, ca. 1905 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Seven prints depicting scenes from the Pan Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1915 (Folder 36: 3)
  - One print depicting a sail boat, San Francisco Bay, 1952 September 21 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Two prints depicting the exterior of the Pacific Coast Stock Exchange, San Francisco, California, 1953 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Twenty one prints depicting fossilized human bones collected for research in paleopathology, 1967 (Folder 36: 6)
  - Thirty one prints depicting fossilized human bones collected for research in paleopathology, 1967 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Nine prints depicting a mock statue made in honor of Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 36: 8)
  - One print depicting the residence of Leo Eloesser's grandparents, San Francisco, California, undated (Folder 36: 9)
  - Three prints depicting the Alhambra, and one print depicting Salamanca University, Spain, undated (Folder 36: 10)
  - One print depicting a locomotive engine, Tacámbaro, Mexico, undated (Folder 36: 11)
  - Two prints depicting scenes in Pennsylvania, possibly relating to Joyce Campbell's family, undated (Folder 36: 12)
  - Twenty six prints depicting farming and logging activities, undated (Folder 36: 13)
  - Thirty three prints depicting ranching activities, undated (Folder 36: 14)
  - Eighteen prints depicting the construction of Hoover Dam, undated (Folder 36: 15)
  - Six prints depicting a farm in Mexico, undated (Folder 36: 16)
  - Seven prints depicting scenes in Ireland, undated (Folder 36: 17)
  - Six slides used in a lecture by Leo Eloesser, "Some Early American Chest Surgery," Stanford University, 1966 (Folder 36: 18)
- Photographs, 1975-1987.
  Compact sound cassettes, arranged chronologically
  - One compact sound cassette containing an interview with Leo Eloesser, San Francisco, 1975 October 7 (Folder 36: 19)
  - One compact sound cassette, "Sexteto Boloña: La historia del son cubano, vol. 1,", 1987 (Folder 36: 20)
- Motion Pictures, 1929. (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  Film reels, arranged chronologically
  - Three film reels relating to Leo Eloesser and sailing, undated (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  - One film reel, "Dr. Eloesser—Vertebral Bone Graft,", undated (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  - One film reel relating to China, n.d. (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  - One film reel marked empty, undated (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  - One film reel, "S.F.—Panama May 1929," (Film-shelf Film shelf)
- Art Works, 1905-1976.; See also Oversize Materials
  Cards, postcards, sketches, monograph, and watercolors, arranged by physical form.
  - By Leo Eloesser
    - Sketchbooks, undated (Folder 37: 1-2)
    - Sketch, "Pater,", undated (Folder 37: 3)
    - Self-portrait, Moscow, 1905 (Folder 37: 4)
    - Twelve sketches of scenes in Spain, 1925
      - Originals (Folder 37: 5)
      - Photocopies (Folder 37: 6)
    - Two sketches of scenes in Manchuria, 1935 (Folder 37: 7)
      Photocopies
    - Three sketches of miscellaneous scenes, 1936-1945. (Folder 37: 8)
    - Five sketches of scenes in China, 1946-1949
      - Originals (Folder 37: 9)
      - Photocopies (Folder 37: 10)
    - Sketch, "Ready for the Stomach Tube,", 1976 March 20 (Folder 37: 11)
  - By others
    - Four portraits of unidentified persons, possibly relatives of Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 37: 12)
    - Sketchbook, possibly belonging to Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 37: 13)
    - Watercolor by Alfred Franstadt(?), undated (Folder 37: 14)
    - Five postcards depicting paintings by Frida Kahlo, undated (Folder 37: 15)
    - Thirteen postcards depicting paintings by Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 37: 16)
    - One postcard depicting Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, undated (Folder 37: 17)
    - Christmas card with illustration by Jean Charlot, undated (Folder 37: 18)
    - Eight prints depicting paintings by Pedro Figari, undated (Folder 37: 19)
    - Siqueiros: 13 grabados, album with original woodblock prints by David Alfaro Siqueiros, 1931 (Folder 37: 20)
    - Watercolor by unknown artist, 1933 (Folder 37: 21)
    - Six hand painted Christmas cards with illustrations by Native American artists, commissioned by Leo Eloesser, 1937 (Folder 37: 22)
    - Herrera Maclean, Carlos A., Pedro Figari, 1943. (Folder 37: 23)
      Contains reproductions of paintings by Figari
- Printed Matter, 1906-1983. (Box 38)
  Chapbooks, monographs, and serial issues, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Brazilian chapbooks
    - Anonymous
      - História de uma criança profeta nascida em Minas Geraes, undated (Folder 38: 1)
      - História do valente sertanejo Zé Garcia, undated (Folder 38: 2)
      - O matuto vendendo fumo, undated (Folder 38: 3)
    - Cordeiro Sobrinho, José, Uma avalanche comunista ou a prisão do Cardial Primaz, undated (Folder 38: 4)
    - Ferreira, Caetano
      - História da emissaria de Allah ou a vitima do orgulho, undated (Folder 38: 5)
      - Peleja de José Cordeiro Sobrinho com Caetano Ferreira, undated (Folder 38: 6)
    - Gomes de Barros, Leandro, A força do amor ou Alonso e Marina, undated (Folder 38: 7)
    - Milanez da Silva, Severino, História de Valentão do mundo e a princesa Edileuza, undated (Folder 38: 8)
    - Pacheco, José
      - Dois glosadores: Barra-Mansa e Torce-Bola, undated (Folder 38: 9)
      - Grande debate que teve Lampeão com S. Pedro, undated (Folder 38: 10)
    - Paula, Francisco Firmino de, História do boi leitão ou o vaqueiro que não mentia, undated (Folder 38: 11)
    - Santos, Manoel Camilo dos, Conselho a os solteiros, undated (Folder 38: 12)
    - Silva, José Bernardo da, O casamento de Zé Miolo com Chica Pelada, undated (Folder 38: 13)
    - Vasconcelos, Alceu Cabral de, Porque faz mêdo casar, undated (Folder 38: 14)
    - Athayde, João Martins de, Os dramas tragicos do Recife antigo, 1938 (Folder 38: 15)
    - Lima, João Ferreira de, Dois poetas glosanda: Zumba Cordeiro e José Bentivi, 1948 (Folder 38: 16)
      Two copies
    - Silva, José Bernardo da Silva, O preguiçoso que tudo quer sem trabalhar, 1948 (Folder 38: 17)
    - Amaral, Firmino Teixeira do, Peleja do Cego Aderaldo com Zç Pretinho do Tucum, 1949-1950 (Folder 38: 18)
    - Athayde, João Martins de, O principe e a fada, 1949 (Folder 38: 19)
    - Cordeiro, José, Perseguições de Lampeão pelas forças legaes, 1949 (Folder 38: 20)
    - Gomes, Abilio Gregório, A intriga de cachorro com o gato, 1949 (Folder 38: 21)
    - Lima, João Ferreira de, História de Mariquinha e José de Souza Leão, 1949 (Folder 38: 22)
    - Pachêco, José, A propaganda do matuto com um balaio de maxixe, 1949 (Folder 38: 23)
    - Silva, José Bernardo da
      - O Casamento de Zé Miolo com Chica Pelada, 1949 (Folder 38: 24)
      - História de Gedeão e Guiomar, 1949 (Folder 38: 25)
      - Mariana e o capitão do navio, 1949 (Folder 38: 26)
    - Anonymous, Romance do pavão mysterioso [sic], 1950 (Folder 38: 27)
    - Athayde, João Martins de
      - A filha das selvas, 1950 (Folder 38: 28)
      - Peleja de João Athayde com Raymundo Pelado do Sul, 1950 (Folder 38: 29)
    - Gustavo, José, Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia, 1950 (Folder 38: 30)
    - Milanês da Silva, Severino, Peleja de Severino Pinto com Severino Milanês, 1950 (Folder 38: 31)
    - Silva, José Bernardo da
      - ABC do amor, 1950 (Folder 38: 32)
      - Continuação do papagaioi misterioso, 1950 (Folder 38: 33)
      - O ladrão de Bagdé, 1950 (Folder 38: 34)
      - O principe Oscar e a rainha das aguas, 1950 (Folder 38: 35)
  - Monographs
    - In Chinese
      - 1944-1947 (Folder 38: 36)
      - 1974-1975 (Folder 38: 37)
    - In Chinese and English (bilingual editions), ca. 1925 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
    - In English
      - Undated (Folder 39: 3)
      - 1906 (Folder 39: 4)
      - 1923 (Folder 39: 5)
      - 1924 (Folder 39: 6)
      - 1929 (Folder 39: 7)
      - 1930 (Folder 39: 8)
      - 1935 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
      - 1937 (Folder 40: 3)
      - 1938 (Folder 40: 4-7)
      - 1939 (Folder 40: 8-9)
      - 1940 (Folder 40: 10)
      - 1940 (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 41: 2)
      - 1942 (Folder 41: 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 41: 4)
      - 1946 (Folder 41: 5)
      - 1947 (Folder 41: 6)
      - 1950 (Folder 42: 1-3)
      - 1958 (Folder 42: 4)
      - 1960 (Folder 42: 5-6)
      - 1983 (Folder 42: 7)
    - In Spanish (Box 43)
      - Undated (Folder 43: 1)
      - 1916 (Folder 43: 2)
      - 1937 (Folder 43: 3-4)
      - 1938 (Folder 43: 5)
      - 1940 (Folder 43: 6-7)
      - 1946 (Folder 43: 8)
      - 1949 (Folder 43: 9)
      - 1950 (Folder 43: 10-11)
      - 1952 (Folder 43: 12)
      - 1965 (Folder 43: 13)
    - Serial issues. In Spanish
      - 1945 (Folder 43: 14)
      - 1952 (Folder 43: 15)
- Oversize Materials., 1919-1980s. (Box 44)
  Art works and handicrafts; maps; photographs; memorabilia; and miscellany, all arranged by physical form
  - Art works and handicrafts
    - Ceramic, China, undated. (Folder 44: 1)
      One glazed clay bowl used for washing brushes.
    - Drawings and calligraphy (Box 45)
      - Two drawings by Jean Charlot, 1924 (Folder 45: 1)
      - One album of calligraphy presented to Leo Eloesser, China, 1940s (Folder 45: 2)
      - One sheet of tissue paper with calligraphy, China, 1940s (Folder 45: 3)
      - One drawing of a soldier, China, 1940s (Folder 45: 4)
      - One sheet of calligraphy in oracle bone script, China, 1946. (Folder 45: 5)
        Includes typescript
    - Paintings.
      See below for more paintings on Art Racks
      - One framed painting illustrating a story from Confucius, "Crossing the Waterfall with Loyalty and Honesty," China, undated (Folder 45: 6)
      - One watercolor depicting a man with a crane, China, 1940s (Folder 45: 7)
    - Prints and reproductions
      - One woodblock print by Utagawa Hiroshige, Japan, undated (Folder 45: 8)
      - One portfolio depicting makeup used in Chinese opera, undated (Folder 45: 9)
      - One reproduction of a print by Daumier depicting Don Quixote and Sancho Panza, undated (Folder 45: 10)
      - Two illustrations by Daumier, undated (Folder 45: 11)
      - One framed engraving depicting a panorama of Heidelberg, Germany, undated (Folder 45: 12)
      - Four sheets of funerary money, China, undated (Folder 45: 13)
      - Three calendar reproductions of paintings by Diego Rivera, 1939 (Folder 45: 14)
      - Four prints depicting kitchen potentates, China, ca. 1944-1945 (Folder 45: 15)
      - Four sheets of votive money, China, ca. 1944-1950 (Folder 45: 16)
      - One woodblock print depicting a cooperative clinic, China, 1944 (Folder 45: 17)
      - One woodblock print, "Revenge for the Dead," China, 1944-1945 (Folder 45: 18)
      - One woodblock print, "Teaching the Midwives," China, 1945 (Folder 45: 19)
    - Scrolls and rubbings (Box 46)
      - One scroll painting depicting a landscape, China, undated (Folder 46: 1)
      - One scroll with text by Li Mao Cai, China, undated (Folder 46: 2)
      - One scroll painting depicting an orchid, China, undated (Folder 46: 3)
      - One scroll depicting a waterfall, China, undated (Folder 46: 4)
      - One scroll painting depicting a radish, China, undated (Folder 46: 5)
      - Ten charcoal rubbings, China, undated (Folder 46: 6-15)
      - One charcoal rubbing with calligraphy, China, undated (Folder 46: 16)
      - Two scrolls presented to Leo Eloesser, with mock Chinese calligraphy, ca. 1948 (Folder 46: 17-18)
    - Textiles (Box 47)
      - Three pieces of embroidered cloth, China, undated (Folder 47: 1-3)
      - One boy's festival jacket, China, undated (Folder 47: 4)
      - One piece of cloth with embroidered scenes from the life of Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 47: 5)
      - Three small cloth portraits depicting Norman Bethune, Mao Zedong, and Lu Xun, China, ca. 1980s (Folder 47: 6-9)
  - Maps. Two maps depicting sections of the Stanislaus and Calaveras rivers in California, undated (Box-folder 48: 1-2)
  - Photographs (Box 49)
    - Three printed copies of a magazine reproduction of a photograph depicting Leo Eloesser, ca. 1940 (Folder 49: 1)
    - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and fellow doctors, Argentina(?), ca. 1943 (Folder 49: 2)
    - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with medical students, China, 1946 January (Folder 49: 3)